Anthony F. C. Wallace Papers 1920-2000 Mss.Ms.Coll.64a
American Philosophical Society
- Series IV. Works by Wallace, ca.1937-1999; 8 linear feet (Box 115-132)
  - C. Juvenilia
    - Bum, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Caesar's Funeral, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Chinese Birthday, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Christmas Customs, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Church at Stiegel's Run, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Culture: Early Notes on, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Czar, The, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Day, A, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Dead Ship, The, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Devil in Jordan County, The (A Little Town), Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Dickybird's Best Flight, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Education of Wang, The, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Elements, The, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - End of Red Arrow, The, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - End of the World, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Famous Ghost of Cabin One, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Fires Never Burn (idea for one-act play), Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Genius, The, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Hangman's Time, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Hazard of Jungle Island, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Hut, The, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - I am a Man: A Political Essay, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - I Like to Read Dickens, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Join or Die, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Joseph in Agypten, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Julius Caesar, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Last Miracle, The, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Lectures and Discussion, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Man Who Killed, The, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Man Who was Brave, The, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Memory of Beauty, The, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Memory, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Mickey Mouse and Me, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Midwinter Nightmare, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Mistake, The, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Morale is a Woman's Business, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - My Impression of a Modern Radio Interview, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Mystery of the Seven Careless Men, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Nature in Homer, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - On Washington's Farewell Address, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Owl, The, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Philosophy of Enjoyment vs. the Philosophy of Desire, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Plots, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Poems, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Professor Poppycock: An Ill-Humored Play, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Pyramids of Destiny, The, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Rain of Death, The, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Real Hiawatha, The, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Rock, The, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Ruins of Warsaw, The, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Saga of Olaf, The, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Satchuivalia, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Scientific Attitude, The (i.e. Laughter), Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Sea of Faith, The, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Sequel to Murder, A ("description of character or the start of the story"), Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Sheik's House Party, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Skull, The, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Sloane Comes to the End of His Trail, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Spanish Summer Afternoon, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Spy, The, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Story fo the Three Apples, The, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Story of Private Diu, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Third from the Sun, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Ticket for San Francisco, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Unfinished Mss., Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Untitled Play, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Upon My Soul!, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Variation on a Theme, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - War in the Fourth Dimension, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Weak Man, The, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Will O' the Wisp, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - William Saroyan, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Wind, Sand, and Stars Book Review, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Work, The Fight, The, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Wrong Side of the Bed, The, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Years of the Heart, The, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
- Series V. Works by Others, ca.1950-1988; 1 linear foot (Box 133-134)
  Manuscripts, reprints, and reviews by colleagues of Anthony F.C. Wallace. Most works by others appear throughout other series; this series consists of those that Anthony F.C. Wallace maintained separately.
  - On the Fundamental Consanguineal Numbers and their Structural Basis, 1972; Atkins, John
  - Romney and D'Andrade on American Kinship Terms, Atkins, John
  - Wallace Review of Bolton Mansucript on Hypoglycemia and Aggression, Bolton, Ralph
  - Reprints, Burger, Henry G. 1923-
  - Reprints and Proposal for Center for Advanced Study in Religion and Science (CASIRAS), Burhoe, Ralph Wendell 1911-
  - General Neurosis of Mankind, Caspary, William R., 1937-
  - On the Concepts of "Culture Area" and "Language-Culture", Chaney, Richard Paul
  - "Referote" on the Second of Freud's "Three Contributions to the Theory of Sex", Cohen, Samuel
  - Biological Study of Behaviour: Some References, Freeman, Derek
  - Shaman and Incubus, 1965; Freeman, Derek
  - Social Anthropology and the Scientific Study of Human Behaviour, Freeman, Derek
  - Function of Ritual as Social Communication in Animal and Human Societies, Funaro, James
  - Religion and Psychology, Goodenough, Erwin Ramsdell, 1893-1965
  - First Approximation of Supportive and Assimilative Aspects of Santeria in Southern Florida, Halifax, Joan
  - Human Relations Area Files and Cross-Cultural Survey Society Lists, Human Relations Area Files, Inc.
  - The Forbidden Path: Teedyuscung's Embassy to the Western Indians in 1760. Edited by William A. Hunter. With a Sketch of the Indian Background by John Witthoft, State Anthropologist, 1951; Hunter, William A. (William Albert), 1908-
  - Structuring of Aberrant Behavior in a Messianic Cult and in Pathogenic Families; also abstract of The Use of Overseas Indian Populations for Study of the Epidemiology of Hypertension, Katcher, Aaron
  - Structuring of Aberrant Behavior in a Messianic Cult and in Pathogenic Families; also abstract of The Use of Overseas Indian Populations for Study of the Epidemiology of Hypertension, Katcher, Joan
  - Republican Revival Debate--Private Economic Power, the Forgotten Factor, 17 items; Kendall, Walter
  - Schizophrenia: Senses, Sensations, and Sense, Kint, Margaret
  - Toward a Unified Biocultural Theory of Schizophrenia, Kint, Margaret
  - Impact of the Relational Outlook on the Science of Anthropology, Melko, Matthew
  - Second Thoughts about Barth's Models, Paine, Robert, 1926-
  - Religious Autobiographies of Juliana (Parsons) Horsfield and Johanna Christiana (Zeidig) Parsons, Parsons family
  - Determinism of Dam construction of the Rhone Beaver (handwritten translation from French), Richard, Paul-Bernard
  - Notes and Articles, Roheim, Géza, 1891-1953
  - Cognition and Archaeology: A Preliminary Statement, Sabloff, Jeremy A.
  - Componential Analysis of a Tzotzil Maya Kinship System, Salovesh, Michael
  - Mechanism of "Conversion," The, Sargant, William Walters
  - Some Cultural Group Abreactive Techniques and their Relation to Modern Treatments, Sargant, William Walters
  - Therapeutic Biologique, Sargant, William Walters
  - Maya Collapse Revisited: Internal and External Perspectives, Sharer, Robert J.
  - Frank Speck (1881-1950): "White Indian Anthropologist", Smith, Donald
  - Diversity, Tesmer, Floyd
  - The Forbidden Path: Teedyuscung's Embassy to the Western Indians in 1760. Edited by William A. Hunter. With a Sketch of the Indian Background by John Witthoft, State Anthropologist, 1951; Witthoft, John
- Series VI. Consulting and Committee Work, 1951-1995; 10 linear feet (Box 135-153)
  Materials relating to Anthony F.C. Wallace's private consulting work and his affiliation with various professional organizations, government agencies, and committees from 1951 through 1995, including minutes, reports, correspondence, and other administrative records for the following:
  American Academy of Arts and Sciences
  American Anthropological Association (President, 1971-1972)
  American Association for the Advancement of Science: Chairman, Section H
  American Philosophical Society: Committee on Library
  Commonwealth of Pennsylvania Mental Health Research Foundation: Research Advisory Committee
  Foundation's Fund for Research in Psychiatry: Board of Directors
  National Institute of Mental Health: Behavioral Science Study Section
  National Institute of Mental Health: Fellowship Review Panel, Behavioral Sciences
  National Research Council: Committee on Disaster Studies
  National Research Council: Division of Behavioral Sciences
  National Science Foundation: Social Science Research Advisory Committee, (chairman 1970-1971)
  New Jersey Neuro-Psychiatric Institute: Technical Advisory Committee
  Philadelphia Housing Authority (Philadelphia, Pa.)
  Surgeon General's Scientific Advisory Committee on Television and Social Behavior
  U.S. Congress, Office of Technology Assessment: Space Program Advisory Panel
  U.S. Office of Education: Environment Panel, Cooperative Research Program
  U.S. Office of Education: Research Advisory Council
  U.S.-U.S.S.R. Commission on the Social Sciences and the Humanities (sponsored by American Council of Learned Societies): U.S. Subcommission on Anthropology
  Veterans Administration Hospital (Perry Point, Md.)
  Woodrow Wilson Center, Smithsonian Institution: Advisory Council, Program in American History and Culture
  Although the committee files contain a great deal of routine administrative correspondence, most include reports of interest to those researching American society and culture in the mid to late 20th century. The American Anthropological Association records contain extensive information on the controversy sparked by government efforts to recruit anthropologists for counterinsurgency efforts in politically volatile nations such as Thailand and include several copies of "underground" or independent political publications. The U.S.-U.S.S.R. records include papers by Russian anthropologists and several items published in the Russian language.
  - A. American Anthropological Association
    - Ad Hoc Committee of Inquiry in Relation to Thailand #1, American Anthropological Association.
    - Ad Hoc Committee of Inquiry in Relation to Thailand #2, American Anthropological Association.
    - Ad Hoc Committee of Inquiry in Relation to Thailand #3, American Anthropological Association.
    - Ad Hoc Committee on Reorganization [of the AAA], American Anthropological Association.
    - American Anthropologist and Publications Committee, American Anthropological Association.
    - Annual Meeting, 1972: "To Do" lists and miscellaneous items, American Anthropological Association.
    - Annual Meeting, 1972: Plans, American Anthropological Association.
    - Annual Reports, American Anthropological Association.
    - Anthropologists for Radical Political Action, American Anthropological Association.
    - Anthropology Newsletter, 1982-1983; American Anthropological Association.
    - Awards Luncheon Remarks, 1971; American Anthropological Association.
    - Brownrigg, Leslie Ann (George Washington University Ethics case), American Anthropological Association.
    - Committee on Ethics of the A.A.A., American Anthropological Association.
    - Constitution and By-Laws of A.A.A.; Professional Ethics statements, American Anthropological Association.
    - Correspondence--A.A.A. matters--Private, American Anthropological Association.
    - Council of the American Anthropological Association, American Anthropological Association.
    - Davenport, William, et. al.--Report of the Ad Hoc Committee of Inquiry in Relation to Thailand, 1971; American Anthropological Association.
    - Deganawidah Quetzalcoaltl University Newspaper, 1971; American Anthropological Association.
    - Department of Health and Human Support Services (U.S.)--Institutional Guide to DHEW Policy on Protection of Human Subjects, American Anthropological Association.
    - Executive Board Meeting: Agenda (Fried, Adams, Helm, Casagrande, A.F.C.W.), 1972; American Anthropological Association.
    - Executive Board Meeting: Minutes, 1971; American Anthropological Association.
    - Executive Board: Agenda, 74th Meeting, 1972; American Anthropological Association.
    - Executive Board: Correspondence and Reports, 1972; American Anthropological Association.
    - Executive Board: Miscellaneous Papers, 74th Meeting, 1972; American Anthropological Association.
    - Finance Committee, 1981; American Anthropological Association.
    - Finance Committee, 1981; American Anthropological Association.
    - Finance Committee, 1982; American Anthropological Association.
    - Finances and Report on Examination: Year Ended June 30, 1980, American Anthropological Association.
    - Finances and Report on Examination: Year ended June 30, 1981, American Anthropological Association.
    - Financial Statements and Correspondence, American Anthropological Association.
    - Harris, Marvin. "Big Bust on Morningside Heights" (issue of The Nation, June 10, 1968, "A Generation Up in Arms", American Anthropological Association.
    - Iroquois Wampum #1, 1960; American Anthropological Association.
    - Iroquois Wampum #2, 1960; American Anthropological Association.
    - Newsletter and Members and Addresses, American Anthropological Association.
    - Planning and Development Committee, American Anthropological Association.
    - Program Editor (A.F.C.W.), American Anthropological Association.
    - Thailand Controversy, American Anthropological Association.
    - Big Bust on Morningside Heights (issue of The Nation, June 10, 1968, "A Generation Up in Arms", Harris, Marvin
    - Anthropology on the Warpath in Thailand (issue of New York Review of Books, November 19, 1970), Jorgensen, Joseph G., 1934-
    - Radical Academic Guide: Perspectives for a Partisan Anthropology, with comment by Mike Seliger (issue of Liberation magazine, November 1971), Moore, John
    - Study of Effects of Herbicide in Vietnam #1, National Academy of Sciences. (U.S.)
    - Study of Effects of Herbicide in Vietnam #2, National Academy of Sciences. (U.S.)
    - Conference: Palo Alto, California, 1971; National Institute of Mental Health, U.S.
    - Science and Government Report (publication), 17 issues, 17 items; Science and Government Report
    - Counterinsurgency Efforts in Thailand, Simon Fraser University (Burnaby, British Columbia)
    - Counterinsurgency Research on Campus Exposed (cover story, issue of Student Mobilizer, April 2, 1970), Student Mobilization Committee to End the War in Vietnam
    - Anthropology on the Warpath in Thailand (issue of New York Review of Books, November 19, 1970), Wolf, Eric Robert, 1923-
  - B. U.S.-Soviet Commission on Anthropology
    - Scholar Exchange Programs and American Council of Learned Societies, Akademiia nauk SSSR (Academy of Sciences, U.S.S.R.)
    - Genetic Structure of Asiatic Eskimos and Coastal Chkchis Compared to that of American Arctic Populations (originally filed under "Soviet Papers"), Alexyev, V.P.
    - Archeology and the Evidence for the Prehistoric Development of Eskimo Culture: An Assessment (originally filed under "American Papers"), Anderson, Douglas
    - Problems of Comparative Studies in Arctic Maritime Cultures on Archaological Data (originally filed under "Soviet Papers"), Arutjunov, S.
    - Subject Matter and Main Trends of Investigation of Culture by Soviet Ethnographers (originally filed under "Soviet Papers"), Bromley, Yu V.
    - Ethnography of Northern North America--Draft (originally filed under "American Papers"), Burch, Ernest S. 1938-
    - Ethnography of Northern North America--Paper (originally filed under "American Papers"), Burch, Ernest S. 1938-
    - Concerns of Cultural Anthropology in the United States (originally filed under "American Papers"), Goodenough, Ward Hunt
    - On the Question of Studying the Cultural Affinities of the Peoples in North Asia and North America (originally filed with "Soviet Papers"), Gurvich, I.S.
    - Rebuilding the Ancient Ice Bridge, Hanlon, Sean
    - Reports and Correspondence, International Research and Exchanges Board
    - Problems in the Physical Anthropology of North American Indians, Eskimos, and Aleuts, Laughlin, William S.
    - Early Man in the New World, MacNeish, Richard S.
    - Assembly of Behavioral and Social Sciences, National Academy of Sciences. (U.S.)
    - Assembly of Behavioral and Social Sciences, National Research Council
    - Correspondence, U.S.-Soviet Commission on Anthropology
    - Expenses, U.S.-Soviet Commission on Anthropology
    - Invitations and Attendance, U.S.-Soviet Commission on Anthropology
    - Meeting (Tarrytown), 1975; U.S.-Soviet Commission on Anthropology
    - Meeting of American Members, 21 March 1977, 24 items; U.S.-Soviet Commission on Anthropology
    - Meeting, 1974 (First), U.S.-Soviet Commission on Anthropology
    - Meeting, 1975 (Second), U.S.-Soviet Commission on Anthropology
    - Minutes and Follow-up Letters, U.S.-Soviet Commission on Anthropology
    - Peopling of the New World--Correspondence, U.S.-Soviet Commission on Anthropology
    - Peopling of the New World--Films, U.S.-Soviet Commission on Anthropology
    - Peopling of the New World--Local Arrangements, U.S.-Soviet Commission on Anthropology
    - Peopling of the New World--Project, U.S.-Soviet Commission on Anthropology
    - Peopling of the New World--Publications, U.S.-Soviet Commission on Anthropology
    - Peopling of the New World--Remarks by Anthony F.C. Wallace, U.S.-Soviet Commission on Anthropology
    - Proposals for Discussion, 1977; U.S.-Soviet Commission on Anthropology
    - Subcommission Meeting, 1975; U.S.-Soviet Commission on Anthropology
    - Subcommissions, U.S.-Soviet Commission on Anthropology
  - C. Other Committees
    - American Antiquarian Society
    - American Indian Ethnohistoric Conference
    - Committee on the Library #1, 1973-1975
    - Committee on the Library #2, 1976-1982
    - Phillips Fund
    - Anthropology Curriculum Study Project
    - Psychiatric Residency Training in Effective Delivery Systems, 1972; Aspen Conference
    - Center for Study of Southern Culture (University of Mississippi)
    - Teacher's College, Columbia University.
    - Commission on Theology and the Frontiers of Learning
    - Foundations Fund for Research in Psychiatry
    - FFRP Board, Foundations Fund for Research in Psychiatry
    - Franklin Institute Project
    - Horizon House Institute for Research and Development
    - 1974-1975, Institute of Early American History and Culture (Williamsburg, Va.)
    - 1976-1977, Institute of Early American History and Culture (Williamsburg, Va.)
    - Institute on Religion in an Age of Science
    - Star Island Conference #2, Institute on Religion in an Age of Science
    - Star Island Meeting #1, 1962; Institute on Religion in an Age of Science
    - Fifth Congress--Publication Data (Business and Finance), 1956; International Congress of Anthropological and Ethnological Sciences
    - Seventh Congress, 1964; International Congress of Anthropological and Ethnological Sciences
    - 1946-1949, Iroquois Conference
    - 1952-1961, Iroquois Conference
    - Langley Porter Neuropsychiatric Institute
    - Medical Education Conference, Massachusetts Institute of Technology.
    - Membership Nominations, National Academy of Sciences. (U.S.)
    - Membership, National Academy of Sciences. (U.S.)
    - 1964-1965, National Academy of Sciences. (U.S.)
    - National Association of Housing Officials U.S.
    - National Endowment for the Humanities.
    - 1971, National Institute of Education (U.S.)
    - Planning Conference, 1971; National Institute of Education (U.S.)
    - Behavioral Sciences Study Section, National Institute of Mental Health, U.S.
    - Fellowship Review Board, National Institute of Mental Health, U.S.
    - Task Force on Homosexuality #1, National Institute of Mental Health, U.S.
    - Task Force on Homosexuality #2, National Institute of Mental Health, U.S.
    - Task Force on Homosexuality #3, National Institute of Mental Health, U.S.
    - Committees #1, National Research Council (U.S.)
    - Committees #2, National Research Council (U.S.)
    - Disaster Studies--Finances and Expenses, National Research Council (U.S.)
    - Disaster Studies--Worcester County Tornado, WTAG (Radio station) Recordings, National Research Council (U.S.)
    - Fellowship Committee, National Research Council (U.S.)
    - Fritz, Charles, National Research Council (U.S.)
    - 1964-1965, National Research Council (U.S.)
    - Advisory Committee for the Social Sciences #1, National Science Foundation, U.S.
    - Advisory Committee for the Social Sciences #2, National Science Foundation, U.S.
    - Annual Report, 1970; National Science Foundation, U.S.
    - Behavioral Sciences Committee, National Science Foundation, U.S.
    - Board Meeting (one letter), 1972; 1 item; National Science Foundation, U.S.
    - Chairman's Report, 1972; National Science Foundation, U.S.
    - Committee on Social Studies, 1976; National Science Foundation, U.S.
    - Problem-Oriented Research, National Science Foundation, U.S.
    - Research Applied to National Needs (RANN) Advisory Committee, National Science Foundation, U.S.
    - Consulting Work, Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission
    - Consulting Work--Cox, Jonathan P., Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission
    - Drug Use in Social and Cultural Perspective, Smithsonian Institution.
    - Conference on Anthropology and Mental Health, Social Science Research Council. Institute in Law and Social Relations.
    - Conference on Culture and Personality, 1955; Social Science Research Council. Institute in Law and Social Relations.
    - Social Studies and Humanities Curriculum Program
    - Meetings, 1955; Society for Applied Anthropology
    - Administrative Information, 1980; Space Program Advisory Panel
    - Drew, Russell C.--U.S. Posture in Space: A Retrospective Assessment, Space Program Advisory Panel
    - Invitation to Serve and Acceptance, Space Program Advisory Panel
    - Logsdon, John M.--Evolution of the U.S. Civilian Space Program, Space Program Advisory Panel
    - Meeting and NASA Presentation, 1980; Space Program Advisory Panel
    - Meeting Information Package, 1980; Space Program Advisory Panel
    - Meeting Summaries, 1980; Space Program Advisory Panel
    - Space Policy and Applications Study Information Package, Space Program Advisory Panel
    - Space Policy and Applications Workshops, 1981; Space Program Advisory Panel
    - United States. Congress. Office of Technology Assessment--Annual Report, 1980; Space Program Advisory Panel
    - Surgeon General's Scientific Advisory Committee on Television and Social Behavior
    - Correspondence, Memoranda, etc., Surgeon General's Scientific Advisory Committee on Television and Social Behavior
    - Wallace, A.F.C.--Comments, Surgeon General's Scientific Advisory Committee on Television and Social Behavior
    - Social Structure and Group Behavior in Extended Duration Space Missions, Texas Christian University. Institute of Behavioral Research
    - Grant Panel #1, 1962-1963; U.S. Office of Education
    - Grant Panel #2, 1964-1965; U.S. Office of Education